yo can anyone see this I've never used
periscope before
so I'm in the car on the way to self
racing cars open pilot is driving right
now but of course you know I have to pay
attention at all times that's how the
systems work yeah I'll let you know if
it makes mistakes
[Music]
I'm not really sure like what do and I
can't really use my phone very much
because I'm in the car of course I'm not
you know I have my phone mounted in a
mount it's hands-free
so hopefully you all can hear me this is
this is open pilot driving right now I
also have the six minute timeout so
we're about three minutes through the
six minute timeout we are cruising you
know people always like you know there's
all these demo videos and they're
they're so like curated this is real
this is open pilot driving all right
excellent I'm cool I think if I double
tap
does that work hey what's up uh yeah I'm
driving uh hang on we go put the speed
up
so let's go back here to the road
see see there's a car the air was gonna
stop for it I put the speed up so that
resets my six-minute meter to show that
I can pay attention oh yeah let me know
let me know what y'all want to see the
truth is driving is boring especially
driving in this lake stop and go traffic
see we got some BOTS dots up here you
guys can't see quite seeing the right
lane so we came to a full stop here can
you see the Neo um quickly if I'm
stopped sure here's an amount here no it
stays dead straight no ping-pong in the
lane so it's it's entirely the car I'll
let you know if I have to intervene at
all
the longest drive was probably two and a
half hours straight that was on the
comma zero that was on the old system
[Music]
and we could check the logs and we could
find like the max engagement record can
I take Ben's on the highway absolutely
um so this car has a slightly raised
torque limit as well we've raised the
torque limit double what this car ships
with which makes it take a bit sharper
bends but even the neo that you build
yeah it could definitely take bends on
the highway you don't get a lot of
updates for me follow us on Twitter yeah
but then steering saturation limits
exact like someone knows how this thing
works
notice great you guys can answer the
questions for me I can't pay that much
attention to the phones obviously I have
to pay attention to the road today you
see things like you know we're gonna go
under this bridge right here and you're
gonna get you're gonna get some shadows
but this is why we have a tempura model
it open pilot so it keeps the lane
straight even when the camera is
adjusting its autofocus we're about
three minutes since I press the button
where's the hardware well my phone is
mounted so my phone is mounted in a
place I use - a chef are you chef er so
get chef or calm down your dash cam app
open pilot for other cars well you have
to go to our website there are bounties
we are sponsoring a bunch of bounties
for other cars the great thing about
open palette is it is open source and it
is well within the community's ability
to port it to other cars and I know this
because I've seen it done
so yeah it's still it's still driving I
mean this is the kind of stuff that's
just grueling to drive in as a human
right you like stepping on the brakes
you got to go a little bit you're
switching from stop and go to go a bit
faster the Civic in front of me is
driving pretty well which is good if the
driver in front of me is being
aggressive it's like aggressively
tailgating is slamming on the brakes and
slamming on the accelerator it's harder
to drive smoothly this is true for both
humans and for the system but um because
that drivers driving well we drive also
so we should get to the six minute
timeout limit we're down we're about
four minutes without of this engagement
I mean you guys are like literally this
wow there's like 40 you watching me
drive in traffic BAM yeah and I got on I
gotta make some turn up ahead but I II
have I tested this on big rigs
oh I don't own a big crank
I don't license to drive a big rig we've
tested it on a Hondas and Acuras
thank you
I feel like a camera
so yeah and you know it's it's you know
it's great that we have the six minute
timeout limit because it really keeps
the driver engaged like the system's
been driving for the last five minutes
so we might get a cut-in up here for
this truck see how late it is
yeah that I cut in from the truck cut in
from the truck all right good job Neal
see that that kind of stuff man
and actually it did that I you know I
saw I looked on the neo I saw that it
saw the truck um that was incredibly
smooth probably smoother than a human
would do it so here we are we're taking
a little bend on the highway
any near-term updates yeah so open pilot
we're gonna get a cut out up here of the
Tacoma we're gonna come back to the
Honda being the lead get away Julie
fully cuts out of the lane and then open
pylons gonna accelerate a bit I can see
on my screen that the lead is switched
over the lawn down a little too hard on
the brakes they're part of that
unfortunately is a hardware limitation
does it plan path for the other vehicle
sorry I missed that that baited I was
watching because there's a lot going on
um yeah it's a little hard on the brakes
here as well but no not bad I'm well
within well within the realm of human
driving I'm so we're about to hit the 6
minute mark if you've watched the video
when we get to 6 minutes my hands so
take control to regain speed I'm just
gonna move the wheel a tiny bit we got a
motorcyclist here he's alright
I'm gonna disengage I don't feel great
around motorcyclists so used to ride one
myself um so we're back to disengage my
hands are back on the wheel and now I'm
gonna re-engage now I put the speed up
to 65 I can show you guys my hands yeah
I'm in an Acura ILX I'm the original ,
Acura ILX we got a light on the roof we
got a high-precision GPS we're back
engaged here in my hands guys know the
Neal will not change lanes so we don't
have any side sensors on the car the
only sensors that the new yoyo my fuel
is low it also won't take me off the
road to stop at a gas station I wonder
how long I have
does it have issues with bicyclists no
it does okay um I don't know just like
as a like I like to you know Drive extra
conservatively around that so I'll
usually take control when there's other
cars like all right so we're gonna get a
late cut into this Elantra here no no no
we're not gonna let them in yeah be
aggressive that's right
uh-oh I'm not switched I'm just showing
you that I'm gonna touching nothing I
guess there's back
when we did all the sonic censors yeah
so you probably can but if your
ultrasonic sensors are on the cars can
bus you could probably use them there's
a corner so I actually get a corner and
you got like like one of them I free
cams bucks calls I know I need to work
out with to take me automatically a gas
station I agree now I gotta find where
gas station is this is a lot of effort
you guys I wish my father could just
like hey phone gas station I gotta go
take me there that'd be cool you know
what'll do that yep change lanes okay I
can change lanes to the left so I
technically don't have to disengage to
change lanes to the left but I'm going
to because I want to accelerate
aggressively wait I might be at a
carpool lane right now I'm in a carpool
lane I shouldn't be here car plus three
or more persons per vehicle Wow unless
like the Neos count as people we're
gonna get back over here
I'm disengaged
[Music]
oh so I really I don't know how far
along I can go without getting gas
either cannoli next three exes yeah
Captain Picard for his computer engaged
I'll probably get sued by Star Trek
right at 50 plus people with me yeah we
gotta go to the gas station man yeah so
back engage you know what I'll do when
I'm at the gas station I'll try to mount
my periscope mmm I'm trying to think
there's nowhere I can really mount it
that I can show you the NiO the road
that my hands are off the wheel and also
read the messages that's the problem I
can't read the messages so I don't know
why I'm in this Lane this guy's going
mad slow
I'll look at that look at that little
trailer
yeah technology should be open how do
you look it's like what are we doing
here right let's we all want the same
thing everyone's gonna get rich off
self-driving cars open-source it um yeah
so this is this is actually running open
pilot 0.3 which is a little bit better
than what you can get with the release
to zero point two point nine but zero
point two putting on is still pretty
awesome and if you build a neo of course
that's going to be an absolutely free
upgrade to 0.3 0.3 is a new model our
machine learning team has been working
super hard on that and 0.3 we're really
starting to use all of our crowdsource
data so we're starting to use the model
that's currently an open pilot was
trained somewhat on the crowdsource data
but a lot still on the original comma
zero data set now we've taken that out
of circulation yeah engineer can
contribute we're really hoping for
contributions and we're working to make
it easier for people to contribute Neos
in the hands of thousands of people
that's the dream that's the dream any
near-term hardware software so we have
the pandas tomorrow at noon
we will be cutting the top 20 on the
leader board and the top 20 on weekly
leader board will be getting free comedy
AI pandas
see the thing is I'm afraid to get off
at any of these exits because I worried
there's gonna be lots of traffic when I
get back on the highway what is a panda
for other EPS cars yeah um so what is a
panda a panda is a car interface so it's
a fairly universal car interface it'll
interface with cars going way way way
back a lot more than just on as and
Acuras and right now what it will do is
it works with our app shipper and it's
really read-only right now it reads all
look this guy's all over the lane line
over the lane line bro go back we're
good needs to look at some gas station
options yeah maybe just periscope have
my location yeah so we've been we've
been engaged again for four minutes so
we're gonna hit the timeout yes
poor so any teams using comma at the
racing car event I mean I think we'll
find out tomorrow oh yeah panda uses the
obd part of on-board diagnostics obd not
ODB it's really easy to say that the
wrong way is like these and these kind
of look similar you really see that
glare going on back there yeah this
Nissan frontiers driving pretty well as
well my hands Burroughs yeah so you can
see that I mean you can see my eyes to
what it's facing you that I really am
spending most of my time looking at the
roads right you cannot grow complacent
with these systems they are level two
systems you know I can't stress that
enough on low gas I saw them about
thirty miles yeah that's kind of what
I'm thinking right let's push it I was
driving this one time I was driving
through middle of Nevada there is
nothing in the middle of Nevada I see a
sign that says next gas station 183
miles
yeah reactions right some reactions so
we can see both cameras I'm so fully
stopped right now now we're starting to
roll again do you guys like seeing the
front camera more the back cover more
pick me up yeah more powerful hardware
and camera suite yeah we're absolutely
looking into it um the big advantage to
staying on a cell phone is cell phones
are very available consumer electronics
so they're easy for people to get right
a building coming I as a relatively
small company building complex hardware
is maybe outside of our reach for I
don't know at least a couple more months
we're building some simple hardware
we're building the Panda we'll see how
that goes on the Panda is the most
advanced way to interface to your car it
has three can buses to Lin buses it
supports GM land
it supports detection of whether the car
started or not on the other oh D beep
ends it's gonna get you so like a lot of
especially electric cars you're talking
like Nissan Leafs and Chevy Volts here
have three can buses on the ODB port and
the three can bus is one of them is the
main can one of them is kind of like the
chassis scan but the other one is the
battery can so we should be able to look
into what's going on in the canvases of
those cars and we should be able to get
the status of all of the batteries
up that's the six minute limit for the
neon so I'm just putting my hands on the
wheel turning it a tiny bit to show the
system that I'm here go back to the
other camera for a little bit you want
to see some action these can reverse
engineering the biggest only barrier to
using kneel on other cars yeah Samsung
phones crash a lot but I'm using a
Samsung phone we're using a 1 plus phone
yeah we're really rolling through
traffic here that's this this this model
is good
um oh I'm super happy like it's keeping
me in the dead center of the lane stop
and go feels pretty good so I was you
have a question before that feel like I
was saying something and then I started
thinking about that got hit by the user
distracted thing it's a six minute
timeout
all right how many sensors we have now
so the only sensors that open pilot use
is about a dead stop right now by the
way the only sensors open pilot uses are
the the camera on the phone and the
front-facing radar that's built into the
car which we access over the canvas cam
I don't know what that means
here we go I like this periscope thing
it's pretty cool what can you not my
cause well there's a bunch of things
I'll first off uh commonly I use real
and let people know this I mean a lot of
people really aren't aware um you know
you'll hear about Google's self-driving
cars yourself of course but you can't
get any of that technology
we got a con in here got a car did you
got a watch ok cool that was that was
plenty backed off and saw that real
early my exposure is so washed out
let's hope we don't get a leg cutting
from that truck he looks aggressive
[Music]
yeah but just that you don't spread the
word about comment and download - Kevin
oh it's called shiver it's available for
both iPhone and Android you can get your
hands on that and you can start camera
chords all your trips and we use that
data to improve open pilot so we have
almost a million miles maybe we'll have
a little periscope our mouse I like
periscope I can you put flyers I don't
know if we're quite there yet
like I look I mean you look at the thing
right now it mostly appeals to people
who want a hack on their cars my hope is
that by the end of the year we will have
support for many more mass-market cars
and we'll do more and more to
incentivize that make that easier as the
year goes on well we've already put up
but I can do more to incentivize that
we've already put up what our bounty
program is and you can check that out
from comedy on our website Wi-Fi yeah of
course of course
Scheffer by default uploads are not gone
not on your mobile data because it would
use way too much of it it waits until
you get back to Wi-Fi it only uploads
over mobile data if you turn that option
on periscope going downhill
did I miss periscope with periscope cool
that he used to be cool so I'm cool
anymore
it's not cool anymore did I miss the
periscope was it cool um yeah no comment
yeah we're real uh and we're we're gonna
hopefully win I mean I think that
there's a lot of noobs in the space and
both cameras are washed out right now I
don't know why all right I should
probably get more serious about this
whole gas station thing so we'll
periscope all the way until we get to
the gas station all right this doesn't
look like it's anywhere near a gas
station I look like if I found like a
sheep around here you know what this
reminds we have Windows XP bliss any
teams in the same fro self racing event
using a neo we are um will be doing a
lap we could do it entirely on the neo
we haven't kind of time in with the
computers we could use the computer to
run some of the processes but really
it's like a distributed architecture you
serialization and we use TCP so we can
go over the network just as easily this
exit Hercules Stockton Stockton scares
me
let's see if we come upon a gas station
really really walking first off we're
going a little faster now this is nice
[Music]
cruise control set at 65 we're going 56
right now and yeah we're about five
minutes in so usually we get to the bar
without a disengagement um I'd say on
average 10 minutes between disengagement
right now obviously if the bar we don't
count us disengagement that's a safety
feature all does a gas station over
there all right there's a cop over there
let's get off the next all right so no
we can do
I'll show you guys like the vaguely
automatically no let's hit the 6 meters
no fools here that's tomorrow the fools
come tomorrow there's an already detect
crash that you raise like the Tesla
thing that was fake news the Tesla thing
there were the Tesla the reason like you
detected a crash situation it's actually
just just the radar tracked a car that
you can't see and I'm gonna get off
Willow Avenue here they disengaged if
you all heard that beep
a carver
let's go green bean each pull us right
back into the lane to slow us down
behind this car yeah we're getting off
right here there's a Burger King to
never get a whopper
I love whoppers so I'm back in control
of the car oh I hit the screen and for
some reason and auto-exposure
there's a Vallejo before the bridge oh
I'm about to hit that bridge oh I know
that bridge am I gonna regret getting
off this exit
I don't think so this looks somewhat
reasonable I'm serious about that
whopper to think I'm playing about the
whopper all right
that's a gas-station straight ahead
right here we got 76
[Music]
I'm gonna stop we get gas get a little
food and maybe I'll be back on periscope
in a bit maybe for some open highway
cruising
now I love periscope this is great I
understand why Martin shkreli likes it
so much should be easier there's a pump
over there but that's on the wrong side
right boss
cool yeah catch you a little bit later I
figure out a stop this thing starts
catch me we'll ask for follow you follow
me bros
I don't know how do I stop this thing
eleven taps key I don't know how to do
this I'm so bad at this